JOSEPH ABIMBOLA AKINWOLE

CONTACT

Address:

Plot 11, Block K, Alaba Layout, off Stateline, Futa South Gate Akure, Ondo State

Phone:

+234(703)6857945

Email:

josey359@gmail.com

INTERESTS

Coding, Chess, Problem-Solving, meeting new friends, Team Play, Fashion design, Art, Music. Singing, Cooking,

Soft Skills Hard Skills

Time Management **HTML** Organization **CSS**

JavaScript

SASS

Languages Bootstrap

Tailwind CSS English ReactJS French **React Native** Spanish

Python Asp.Net core **NodeJS**

Git Repository

https://github.com/Joebim

FULL PORTFOLIO

https://joebim.github.io/Mon-Portfolio/

EDUCATION

Federal University of Oye-Ekiti –

Bachelor's Degree, Linguistics and Languages (majoring in computational linguistics) 2016 - 2021

ABOUT ME

Hi, my name is Joseph, Joe for short and I code 🥚



Languages seemed to be the idea when I started a four-year journey into earning a BA in linguistics, but halfway into my third year, I rooted my passion into coding. Ever since, my life made sense to me. Just at the moment I viewed my first tutorial on the basics of web development, it was just right. Vision spinning in my head like an unending "eureka!".

Seeing coding syntax as a language, I began learning and speaking my way through my journey:). In codes. I enjoy every part of frontend development, from the structure of the code to how each building block of elements can be perfectly placed and designed to form a magnificent UI and how it can be brought to life with lots of data and perfect code. I am well proficient in Reactjs, React-native, NodeJS, mongo DB, SQL and I've master the act of styling with bootstrap, tailwind CSS, Sass and CSS of course. With knowledge on the wonders of git, I can handle code versions or branches in git terms and git command work arounds. I'm currently digging my hands into flutter and I'm really open-minded to acquiring more framework or languages. Like they say, the learning continues.

I cherish the usefulness of wonderful creations in the tech and how it can build a better world in the future and I want to be part of that future.

EXPERIENCE

JD Lab (An EduTech Firm), — Frontend Developer

Niger State, Minna.

Dec 2021 - November 2022

Roles

- Upgraded JSP (JDLab School Portal) A School Management System
 - Implemented all major & minor components of Student and Application Portal with redesigned UI.
 - Handled major User interactions (For Students) and functionalities from payments to results and Admission

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, ReactJS, Bootstrap, Styled-Components

- Handled JDLab Academy
 - Tutored Students on Frontend Development Courses.
 - Handled Classes in JDLab Summer Camp

ICT Community Development Service (NYSC) — Project and Lecture Coordinator

- Co-ordinated all tech related projects
- Tutored members of the ICT CDS in various aspects of tech

Jan 2022 - July 2022

Google Developer Student Club (GDSC) Fuoye — Frontend Web Developer

Nov 2019 - Oct 2021

Freelancer, — Freelance Web Developer & Graphics Designer

Dec 2019 - May 2021

Upwork, — Freelance Web Developer

May 2018 - Nov 2019

PROJECTS

JSP: JDLab School Portal(JSP) is a state-of-the-art management portal that offers all the features you need for your institution. It is a fast clean interface with easy integration

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, ReactJS, Bootstrap, Styled-Components

Link: https://jsp.ng/

Foodipi: A Food website to find recipes for wide varieties of exquisite dishes and manage calories, special diets, nutritional requirements and favorite ingredients with classification of recipes into types and cuisines (in progress) Frameworks: **React.js, JavaScript, HTML, Sass, NodeJS**

Boonie: A skill empowerment app to educate and teach with basic learning techniques, easy skills for self-empowerment in areas of self-interest (in progress)

Frameworks: React.js, JavaScript, HTML, React Native, Tailwind CSS, Sass.

Grexo: Intelligent body measuring tool for Apparel making with adaptive body-shape measurement to 3D apparel conversion (in progress)

Frameworks: React.js, Flutter, Spline.

Vlish: Experience immersive 3D interior Assets, environments and objects in Virtual Reality with Editing Features for interior decoration (in progress)

Frameworks: React.js, Spline, tailwind CSS, Redux.

WORK CERTIFICATION

 GDSC-FUOYE — Frontend Development Certification https://drive.google.com/file/d/1544kEGIHJnoJMVXAB_AYiQ1HHkOVZ_kG/view?usp=sharing (2020)

OTHER CERTIFICATION

- ICT Community Development Service (NYSC) Certificate of Membership of Niger State ICT Community Development Service (CDS).
- Udemy Workplace Ethics and Attitude https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qYkEY25xVkIhS87nEFzwgTcYvZR8KXJu/view?usp=sharing (2022)